A Guide to the Rollin D. Hotchkiss papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA168
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rollin D. Hotchkiss papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
Hotchkiss, Rollin Douglas
FA168
6.16 Cubic Feet 14 boxes.
14 boxes
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Chemical samples received from Professor Rollin D. Hotchkiss, through Mrs. René J. Dubos, May 1982.
General note
Chemical samples (received from Professor Rollin D. Hotchkiss).
Lipids prepared by P.A. Levene:
1139 Sphingosin.
1125 Sphingomyelin Egg.
1145 Sphingosine Sulphate C=63.60 H=11.20 N=3.82 S=3.88
1136 Dihydro Spingosin H2SO.
1123 (partly erased) Sphingomyelin. (_free). C=67.00% H=11.40% N=3.42% P=3.55%
1076 Lignoceric Acid Best.
1074 Lignoceric Acid Amide.
1077 Lignoceric Acid.
1097 Lignoceric Acid. Sphingomyelin.
1131 Sphingomyelin Brain.
1126 Sphingomyelin Kidney.
1155 Psychosin.
1115 Phrenosin. C=69.21% H=10.62%.
1116 Phrenosine Crystal.
1124 Sphingomyelin. C=65.50% H=10.76% N=3.50% P=3.92%.
1135 Dihydro Spingosin Urea.
1138 Sphingosin. Free.
1148 Sphingosine Sulphate.
1140 Sphingosine.
Other samples:
Tyrot___icin 10 gr.
Tyrothricin Standard. (Sample #121). 12/19/1944.
Wallerstein Company... Special Tyrothricin Defatted. 15 gms. See ltr. dtd. October 23, 1951 to Dr. R.J. Dubos.
Gramicidin. Crystalline. Wallerstein Labs. 5 Grams. M.P. 228°C. 11-30-1944.
Gramicidin, moderately pure. 1.5 g. RDH.
Samp. #303. 1.0 gms. Gramicidin (competitive).
N__ desoxycholyl Amine. 2 g.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 H797
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: biographical material, correspondence, subject files, lectures, notes, reprints, and manuscripts.
Arrangement
As received.
Biology -- Research; DNA; Biochemistry; Genetics; Chemistry; Medical sciences; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Life sciences; Medical research; Medical education
- Biographical materials, 1
  - Bibliography, 1936-1980; 11 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abstracts, book reviews, etc., 1950-1979; 2 pp. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographies (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Naval service, 1941-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Congratulations promotion to Member, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Honorary degrees Yale 1962, Hungarian Academy of Sciences 1976, University of Paris 1980, 1962-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - NY Times Magazine article, with photos of RDH lab, 1958 November 23
    - Charles O. Beckmann
    - Manci Kohoutová - family and lab staff
    - Mendel Museum, Brno
    - RDH, Sold Goodgal, Norton Zinder at Oak Ridge, circa 1968
- Correspondence files, 2
  - Cavalieri, Liebe F. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Felicitations sent and received (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Florida, University of Research and lectures, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Kaiser, Dale, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kalckar, Herman M. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Kohoutová, Manci (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nobel Committee [Nominations], 1961-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Personal letters, mostly to RDH from members of lab, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Public, letters from
    - re genetic engineering (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - high school biology (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - miscellaneous letters about other than genetics, DNA (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Special letters (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Related Materials
    See Appendix I end of listing for description.
- The Rockefeller Institute and University, 3
  - RU, RDH in, 1935-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Academic courses participated in (Cold Spring Harbor, RU, Berkeley, NYU), 1955-1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Leaves of absence, visiting professorships (MIT, Corpus Christi, Hungary, Utah), 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence with colleagues (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Avery, O.T.
    - RDH article for Genetics, includes reprint, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - start of file (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dubos, René J.
    - Personal letters, 1942-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Memorial, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fox, Maurice S., 1952-1967 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Granick, Sam Memorial, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Nozawa, Ryushi (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Roger, Muriel
    - NSF grant procedural, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Public record", 1960-1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - RU record (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Memorial, includes MS of RDH talk, 1982 April 5 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Szilard, Leo (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Tomasz, Alexander
    - Correspondence re, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Progress in RU, 1960-1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Wolf, Beverly, 1958-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Woolley, D.W. [primarily material collected by Dr. E.L. Tatum for a biography of Dr. Woolley for the NAS] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Associates of Hotchkiss-Zinder labs, 1954 1960-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Scope and Contents note
    [Does not include unsalaried visitors nor unplanned 2-3 mos, visitors or consultants, if any]
  - Chemical procurement (donated samples), 1942-1947 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Commencement talks by RDH (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Judicial Committee
    - "A Brief History..." RDH, 1983 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Incorporation of the J.C., 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Official files of the J.C. (incomplete), circa 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Official university reaction to the J.C. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Reactions to the J.C. by faculty and students, circa 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Student
    - Greco, Frank Ph. D. 1981 (Mauro) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Kent, Joan Ph. D., 1960-1981 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Lacks, Sanford Ph. D., 1956-1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Mindich, Leonard Ph. D. 1962, 1955-1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Ortiz, Priscilla J., 1957-1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Ottolenghi (Nightingale), Elena Ph. D., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Student interviews and thesis examinations A-Z See Appendix II for listing (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Students, miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 20)
      [see Appendix II for listing]
    - Vietnam protest and student activist protests at RU (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Student reports or summaries of course work, circa 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - RDH lectures and reports/RI/RU
    - Scientific reports after 1954, 1954 1936-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
      [includes bibliographies ca 1936-61]
    - Scientific reports, 1936-1947 (Box 4, Folder 2a)
    - RDH lecture at RU, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - RU Memorabilia
    - University News, SUNY Albany 26 January 1983 "Ilchman Names First Director of Rockefeller Institute", 1983 January 26 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Subject files, 4
  - Committees
    - National Cancer Institute (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - NRC Committee on Recombinant DNA and laboratory-associated risks (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Szeged (Hungary, Biological Center (UNESCO) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Viking experiments (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Conferences and congresses
    - Assembly conference (Szeged, Hungary), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - International Genetics Congresses
      - 12th, Tokyo (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - 13th, Berkeley (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - 14th, Moscow (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - International Joint Conference of the American Geographical Society and the American Division of the World Academy of Art and Science (1st and 2nd) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Editorial correspondence
    - Adams, Mark Posthumous book on bacteriophage (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Portugal-Cohen book (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Submitted mss of others for publication (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Journals
    - Biochemistry, J. Cell Biology (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Reference letters
    - A-B (Box 5, Folder 2)
      [See Appendix I for listings]
    - C-E (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - F-K (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - L-N (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - O-R (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - S-Z (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Societies
    - American Society for Cell Biology (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - American Society of Naturalists (Box 5, Folder 9)
- RDH Writings and Lectures, 5
  - Correspondence re RDH papers and lectures (Box 5, Folder 10-12)
  - Invitations for articles, books, reviews (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Permissions (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - RDH lectures before, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lectures, 1961 1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sigma Xi lectures, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - MSS 1951 Cold Spring Harbor "classic" paper (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - MS Encyclopedia Americana "Tyrothricin" article, circa 1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - MS (partial, with correspondence) Ann. Rev. Gen. "Bacterial Transformation", circa 1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Abstracts, circa 1950-1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous mss, abstracts for papers, and remarks (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous mss, unpublished (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Gramicidin mss and abstracts (Box 6, Folder 9a)
- Laboratory notes and notebooks, 6
  [Note: 1 canister synthetic polymer samples [See RDH notes in (6) 9] ]
  - Laboratory notebooks, circa 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Detergent experiments (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Khorana experiments (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Reprints and Manuscripts, 7; 2 2 1/2 in. boxes
  - Reprints and select manuscripts (Box 12)
  - Reprints and select manuscripts (Box 13)
- Addition to the collection: Lipids and other samples
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Chemical samples received from Professor Rollin D. Hotchkiss, through Mrs. Rene J. Dubos, May 1982.
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to chemical samples.
  - Lipids prepared by P.A. Levene (Box 14)
    - Sphingosin, 1139
    - Sphingomyelin Egg, 1125
    - Sphingosine Sulphate C=63.60 H=11.20 N=3.82 S=3.88, 1145
    - Dihydro Spingosin H2SO4, 1136
    - Sphingomyelin. (____free). C=67.00% H=11.40% N=3.42% P=3.55%, 1123
    - Lignoceric Acid Best., 1076
    - Lignoceric Acid Amide., 1074
    - Lignoceric Acid., 1077
    - Lignoceric Acid. Sphingomyelin., 1097
    - Sphingomyelin Brain, 1131
    - Sphingomyelin Kidney, 1126
    - Psychosin, 1155
    - Phrenosin. C=69.21% H=10.62%, 1115
    - Phrenosine Crystal, 1116
    - Sphingomyelin. C=65.50% H=10.76% N=3.50% P=3.92%, 1124
    - Dihydro Spingosin Urea, 1135
    - Sphingosin. Free., 1138
    - Sphingosine Sulphate., 1148
    - Sphingosine., 1140
  - Other samples (Box 14)
    - Tarot__icin
      Scope and Contents
      10 gr.
    - Tyrothricin Standard. (Sample #121)., 1944 December 19
    - Wallerstein Company. Special Tyrothricin Defatted.
      15 gms. See ltr. dtd. Oct. 23, 1951 to Dr. R.J. Dubos.
    - Gramicidin. Crystalline. Wallerstein Labs., 1944 November 30
      5 grams. M.P. 228 degress Celsius.
    - Gramicidin. Moderately pure.
      1.5 g. RDH.
    - Samp. #303.
      1.0 gms. Gramicidin (competitive).
    - N__ desoxy cholyl Amine.
      2 g.
- Addition to the collection (Box 7)
  Received 17 July 1984 from Dr. Hotchkiss.
  - Biographical - clippings (Box 7)
  - Biographical - Honorary degrees (Box 7)
  - RI/RU (Box 7)
    - Correspondence with colleagues (Box 7)
    - Positions, correspondence re (Box 7)
    - 63rd St. Subway (Box 7)
    - Students, correspondence with (Box 7)
    - Students, evaluations of (Box 7)
  - Committees-General (Box 7)
  - Committees-Sloan Kettering (Box 7)
  - Genetic Engineering (Box 7)
  - Journals (Box 7)
  - RDH Writings (Box 7)
    - Permissions (Box 7)
    - Reviews of grant and fellowship applications, general (Box 7)
    - Reviews of grant applications on transformation (Box 7)
    - Reviews of manuscripts for Analytical Biochemistry; Biochemistry (Box 7)
    - Reviews of manuscripts on DNA genetic transformation (Box 7)
    - Reviews of manuscripts, miscellaneous (Box 7)
- Addition to the collection
  Materials received 1 November 1985 from Dr. Hotchkiss
  - Mishra, Nawin (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Kashmiri, S.V.E. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Yehle, Clifford (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - de Luca, Chester (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Satir, Birgit (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - International Genetics Congress, The Hague, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Institute for Cancer Research (ICR) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Journal of Biochemistry (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Society of Cell Biology, Journal of Cell Biology (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Szeged, Hungary (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Ledbetter, M.L. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Experimental work with Khorana, project on oligonucleotide synthesis, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Laboratory methods, standardization, etc. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Lab notebook: "Computation Book. I. Gramicidin. September 1940 to September 1941", 1940 September-1941 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Lab notebook: "Computation Book. III. Gramicidin-Tyrocidine Chemistry. September 1941 to [ca 1942]", 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Addition to the collection
  Boxes 9-11 consist primarily of laboratory notes and notebooks.
  - Albany 1986. Photocopies of announcement re RDH honorary degree. School of Public Health Sciences, 21 March 1986; newspaper clipping, ms of RDH remarks, "Cycles in genetics and the academic metabolism", 1986 March 21; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - A61, circa 1937-1938; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 2-4)
  - A62a Staph growth, circa 1945-1948; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - A62b Poisons Miscellaneous, circa 1943-1946; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - A62c Staph, phosphate intake; miscellaneous, circa 1942; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Includes note by RDH 4/86.
  - A62d Staph, mechanism, circa 1943-1946; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - A62e Staph. Radioactive P expts, circa 1943 1946; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - A62f Staph. Phosphate and amino acids, circa 1946-1947; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 10-13)
  - A62g Staph, cell stability, circa 1946-1947; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - A62h Staph, nucleic acid metabolism, circa 1947; 5"Letter (Box 9, Folder 15-16)
  - A62i Macro Staph. Expts. Aerator, circa 1949; 2.5" Letter (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - A62j Staph metabolism. Uracil, purines, circa 1948-1950; 2.5" Letter (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - A62k Staph, amino acid conversion, circa 1946-1948; 2.5" Letter (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
  - A62k, 2.5" Letter (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - A63a Lucy Paige (Sheffield). Lab notes Book #2, 3/18/1965-8/2/1965; 2.5" Letter (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - A63b Lucy Paige. Spiral notebook, 1964 October 29-1965 March 17; 2.5" Letter (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Appendix I: Reference letters
  Details pertaining to the content of Box 5.
  - Adler, Howard, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Atchley, William A., 1953-1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Austrian, Robert, 1958-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bautz, Ekkehard K.F., 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Beiser, Sam M., 1952-1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Benzer, Seymour, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bernheimer, Alan, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Berhheimer, H.P., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Blumberg, Baruch, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brawerman, George, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Gene M., 1960 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cavalieri, Liebe F., 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chargaff, Erwin, 1960 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Clark, Alvin J., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cooper, Stephen, 1962-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Crick, Francis, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Doerfler, Walter, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dubnau, David, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Easton, Thomas G., 1965-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Engelhardt, Dean L., 1964-1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Ephrati-Elizur, Erela, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Erickson, Bob, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fulton, Chandler M., 1965 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Gebe, Karen Ann Coons, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Geronimus, Lippmann H., 1952 1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Ginoza, William, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Goldman, Stephen, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Gots, Joseph, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Gross, Sam, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Guild, W.R., 1957 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hamilton, L.D., 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hartman, Neil, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hartman, Philip E., 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Henderson, James S., 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Kao, Dr., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Kari, C., 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lancefield, Rebecca C., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lark, Cynthia Ann, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lerin, Fernando, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lodish, Harvey F., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Luria, Salvador E., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Maldonado, Héctor, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Marmur, Julius, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Marshak, Alfred, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Morrison, Donald, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Newman, Stuart A., 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nyc, Joseph F., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Oishi, Michio, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Olby, Robert C., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Paigen, Kenneth, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Pieczenik, George, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Rappaport, Harry P., 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Ravin, Arnold, 1956-1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Reiner, John M., 1953 1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Includes S.A. Waksman invitation to RDH for suggestions apropos dedication of Institute of Microbiology at Rutgers University, and RDH reply, 1953-1954
  - Robertson, Hugh D., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Rohinson, Arthur, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Rosenberg, Barbara H., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Satir, Birgit, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Satir, Peter, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Schwartz, James H., 1964 1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Schwartz, Irving, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Setlow, Richard B. and Jane K., 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sheffield, Joel, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sirotnak, Frank, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Strauss, Norman, 1968-1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Talbot, Timothy R., Jr., 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tiraby, Gerard, circa 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Torriani-Gorini, Annamaria, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Wangh, Lawrence, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Weber, Morton M., 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - White, David C., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - [Yale University] re Chandler, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - A. Stetson, Jr., James G. Hirsch
    - J. Maclean Smith, David Rogers
  - [Harvard University] re A.A., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Moscona, Melvin Cohn, Matthew
    - Meselson, and especially Keith R. Porter
  - testimony in support of the Aspen Pathobiology Conferences, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Appendix II: RU Students
  Details pertaining to the content of Box 4 folders 5 and 6.
  - Student interviews and thesis exams (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Burger, Harold, undated
    - Corbet, Aaron, 1969
    - Coyne, Jerry, 1970
    - Derby, Michael, 1969
    - Greene, Levis J., 1962
    - Kent, Joan L., 1963
    - Mather, Jennie, 1969
    - Porter, Charlotte, 1969
    - Powell, Jeffrey, 1969
    - Rabin, Aaron, 1969
    - Rand, James, 1969
  - "Review of: 'Secondary Control of Enzyme Synthesis'. Paper submitted by Levis K. Nading, January 27, 1961. Review by R.D. Hotchkiss, June-July 1961", Carbon typescript, 11 pp., with typed note, 1 p., February 1983 by RDH (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - [Exam in Evolution and Genetics] (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Andrew E. Balber, 1967
    - Nora L. Laiken, 1968